<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Two Hours Late (Posts about just write)</title><link>http://twohourslate.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://twohourslate.com/categories/cat_just-write.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 03:20:42 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Turtle Turds</title><link>http://twohourslate.com/posts/turtle_turds/</link><dc:creator>revo</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="http://twohourslate.com/images/share-preview.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;The world is not knowable. The whole world is knowable only through observation. The only way to observe is in person. In person is being there, and being is the only thing that makes a person experience something. Being there to see it, kinda like life - just here to see it, to see where it leads. Who knows, maybe we are living on a big turtle about to shit a new universe. That the whole universe exists on the inner surface of a bubble from a turtle fart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does the world add up to? What are these rocks, this dirt, trees, concrete, lakes, clouds, birds. Down to the inner core of liquefied iron up to the communication satellites beaming HBO to somebody's 45th floor apartment. Everything in between, every bit of every hundred page email thread and every pixel in every 4KHD bigscreen. From the coffee bean that made it to your palate only after it grew, was picked, shipped, washed, dried, shipped, warehoused, shipped, roasted, bagged, shipped again, measured, brewed, and then thrown away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That coffee bean had a way more interesting life after picking. Or did it? It could have been picked, digested, transported, discarded, buried, moistened, cracked, emerged, grown and revealed again. Can you imagine how few beans enjoy the second route? Very few. Most get consumed by the higher order. All for a short buzz of vibrancy that we could have found by nurturing the bean in its way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nurture nature to get a buzz.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>existential absurdity</category><category>nature</category><category>process</category><category>purpose</category><guid>http://twohourslate.com/posts/turtle_turds/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 06:13:55 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>