<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Two Hours Late (Posts about living 2017)</title><link>http://twohourslate.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://twohourslate.com/categories/living-2017.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 03:20:42 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>What It's Like</title><link>http://twohourslate.com/posts/tell%20me/</link><dc:creator>revo</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;It was 2017 when the world recognized that careers behind keyboards were not self fulfilling but were the ultimate dystopian dream. Unless you were a writer or a Scientist or a Science Writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://twohourslate.com/images/successful_people.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="/images/successful_people.thumbnail.png" src="http://twohourslate.com/images/successful_people.thumbnail.png"&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For everyone else, it became the matrix. No one wanted to be there, but no one could leave. Their bodies were weakened by years of idleness and comfort. Income, insurance and retirement became more critical to sustaining life than did faith, hope and love. In fact, those were just basically make believe relics from a simpler time. There was nothing to have faith in. Sure, there was hope but it wasn't hope for a better tomorrow as much as hope that today would be uneventful. And love... the love that defined humanity was disappearing like the glaciers that had protected the earth from man for 40,000 &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Last_Glacial_Maximum"&gt;years&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love became only for the seekers as most stopped looking long before they could ever construct it. The women who were the weaker sex from the beginning of the species were becoming a dominant force in global affairs. They were strong and they were angry. The men were angry too, but their anger wasn't about what they were losing as much as what they never had. Only children could know happiness and security as their brains were not infused with the sophisticatied model of history that is required to see the world in the hard light of truth. Ahh, truth was the one gem of our age. Everyone lusted after truth. You thought it was money, didn't you? You wouldn't be alone. Most would think it was money, and each would be alone in their dream of fame and fortune. In 1987 it was discovered that money can't buy you love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what exactly does one feel, while living in the year of our lord 2017? One feels very confused. Everything is arbitrary whose reference is static. So static in fact that we no longer are counting forward looking backward, now we're couting backward looking forward. Instead of 2018, it was 2,018 years BP that that thing happend that everyone thought was so important. Isn't it strange that those who think it was important and those who just call it another BP (before present) year will have the same truth and a totally different reference? So, let me pose the question to end all questions. It's also the question that births all questions... it's the virgin birth question... just thought you should know...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does truth exist?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's a long question and time is so short. A smart man says that learning is living and time is always on his side. That would be the outside, by the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="youtube-video"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/jc_oLZuFwaI?rel=0&amp;amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allow="encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;dl class="field-list simple"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Know where to go&lt;span class="colon"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;Written in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/"&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt; on archlinux|ARM_&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;</description><category>living 2017</category><guid>http://twohourslate.com/posts/tell%20me/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 05:43:06 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>