<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Two Hours Late (Posts about struggle)</title><link>http://twohourslate.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://twohourslate.com/categories/struggle.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:52:02 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Capillary Action</title><link>http://twohourslate.com/posts/capillary-action/</link><dc:creator>revo</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Draw me up a design for doing work without doing work. Draw me up a design for making a system capable of doing more work per unit time. This design is the capillary. It is the engine of performance. The capillary establishes a baseline for work that is far above steady state. It draws out what would be content to stay put and carries it up towards higher potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the body, who can say where the capillary stops delivering and starts recovering? With every heartbeat the capillary carries the throbbing life itself into otherwise helpless body. So delicate and easy to damage, yet seemingly ubiquitous and uber-resilient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the transistor there are no wires and yet electricity flows. Charges, fields and currents conspire to influence a single cell of binary information. A capillary of sorts. Beautiful in its simplicity and remarkable in its capability. No, not yet. We also need scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human mind has no limit of scale. If you must, it is quite possible for you to become a single atom. It is just as possible to expand into the entire universe. Which is quite natural, really, since you are just made up of atoms built through the capillary action of now dead stars all across the universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="youtube-video"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Fxv3JoS1uY8?rel=0&amp;amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allow="encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>action</category><category>move</category><category>struggle</category><category>work</category><guid>http://twohourslate.com/posts/capillary-action/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 03:15:30 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>