<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Two Hours Late (Posts by revo)</title><link>http://twohourslate.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://twohourslate.com/authors/revo.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 03:20:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>faster</title><link>http://twohourslate.com/posts/make%20life%20more%20competitive/</link><dc:creator>revo</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;How could it ever be faster to take notes by printing? It is far faster to write with type. This is one of the handicaps of today's youth because they are not able to keep up with the pace of taking notes in class. I used to write like a bandit in class to try to keep up with the professor so that I could pass the test. Apparently, I was just studying to be a writer.
..
What is the fastest stream of consciousness that you have in your toolbox?
..
Which might be faster that you should learn?
..
Which are slower that you should do more often?
..
&lt;em&gt;Google&lt;/em&gt;: 1m01s
.. thumbnail:: /images/speech.png
..
&lt;strong&gt;Typing&lt;/strong&gt;: 1m55s
..
&lt;strong&gt;Printing&lt;/strong&gt;:3m49s
.. thumbnail:: /images/print.jpg
..
&lt;strong&gt;Script&lt;/strong&gt;: 4m34s
.. thumbnail:: /images/script.jpg
..
:Know where to go: Written in &lt;a href="http://twohourslate.com/posts/make%20life%20more%20competitive/#system-message-1"&gt;&lt;span class="problematic" id="problematic-1"&gt;Emacs_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on achlinux|ARM_
.. _ARM: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://archlinuxarm.org/platforms/armv6/raspberry-pi/"&gt;https://archlinuxarm.org/platforms/armv6/raspberry-pi/&lt;/a&gt;
.. _Emacs: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/"&gt;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class="system-messages"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Docutils System Messages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;aside class="system-message" id="system-message-1"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: ERROR/3 (&lt;span class="docutils literal"&gt;&amp;lt;string&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;, line 1); &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://twohourslate.com/posts/make%20life%20more%20competitive/#problematic-1"&gt;backlink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unknown target name: "emacs".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description><category>speed</category><guid>http://twohourslate.com/posts/make%20life%20more%20competitive/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 18:29:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What It's Like</title><link>http://twohourslate.com/posts/tell%20me/</link><dc:creator>revo</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;It was 2017 when the world recognized that careers behind keyboards were not self fulfilling but were the ultimate dystopian dream. Unless you were a writer or a Scientist or a Science Writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://twohourslate.com/images/successful_people.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="/images/successful_people.thumbnail.png" src="http://twohourslate.com/images/successful_people.thumbnail.png"&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For everyone else, it became the matrix. No one wanted to be there, but no one could leave. Their bodies were weakened by years of idleness and comfort. Income, insurance and retirement became more critical to sustaining life than did faith, hope and love. In fact, those were just basically make believe relics from a simpler time. There was nothing to have faith in. Sure, there was hope but it wasn't hope for a better tomorrow as much as hope that today would be uneventful. And love... the love that defined humanity was disappearing like the glaciers that had protected the earth from man for 40,000 &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Last_Glacial_Maximum"&gt;years&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love became only for the seekers as most stopped looking long before they could ever construct it. The women who were the weaker sex from the beginning of the species were becoming a dominant force in global affairs. They were strong and they were angry. The men were angry too, but their anger wasn't about what they were losing as much as what they never had. Only children could know happiness and security as their brains were not infused with the sophisticatied model of history that is required to see the world in the hard light of truth. Ahh, truth was the one gem of our age. Everyone lusted after truth. You thought it was money, didn't you? You wouldn't be alone. Most would think it was money, and each would be alone in their dream of fame and fortune. In 1987 it was discovered that money can't buy you love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what exactly does one feel, while living in the year of our lord 2017? One feels very confused. Everything is arbitrary whose reference is static. So static in fact that we no longer are counting forward looking backward, now we're couting backward looking forward. Instead of 2018, it was 2,018 years BP that that thing happend that everyone thought was so important. Isn't it strange that those who think it was important and those who just call it another BP (before present) year will have the same truth and a totally different reference? So, let me pose the question to end all questions. It's also the question that births all questions... it's the virgin birth question... just thought you should know...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does truth exist?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's a long question and time is so short. A smart man says that learning is living and time is always on his side. That would be the outside, by the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="youtube-video"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/jc_oLZuFwaI?rel=0&amp;amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allow="encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;dl class="field-list simple"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Know where to go&lt;span class="colon"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;Written in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/"&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt; on archlinux|ARM_&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;</description><category>living 2017</category><guid>http://twohourslate.com/posts/tell%20me/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 05:43:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Capillary Action</title><link>http://twohourslate.com/posts/capillary-action/</link><dc:creator>revo</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Draw me up a design for doing work without doing work. Draw me up a design for making a system capable of doing more work per unit time. This design is the capillary. It is the engine of performance. The capillary establishes a baseline for work that is far above steady state. It draws out what would be content to stay put and carries it up towards higher potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the body, who can say where the capillary stops delivering and starts recovering? With every heartbeat the capillary carries the throbbing life itself into otherwise helpless body. So delicate and easy to damage, yet seemingly ubiquitous and uber-resilient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the transistor there are no wires and yet electricity flows. Charges, fields and currents conspire to influence a single cell of binary information. A capillary of sorts. Beautiful in its simplicity and remarkable in its capability. No, not yet. We also need scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human mind has no limit of scale. If you must, it is quite possible for you to become a single atom. It is just as possible to expand into the entire universe. Which is quite natural, really, since you are just made up of atoms built through the capillary action of now dead stars all across the universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="youtube-video"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Fxv3JoS1uY8?rel=0&amp;amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allow="encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>action</category><category>move</category><category>struggle</category><category>work</category><guid>http://twohourslate.com/posts/capillary-action/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 03:15:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Contradictions of Life</title><link>http://twohourslate.com/posts/contradictions-of-life/</link><dc:creator>revo</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;How could this be?
Something from nothing.
Irreducible complexity.
Conservation of energy.
Is it a wave or particle?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are etched into time by an instrument given to us
by no choice of our own. We are empowered through
the
melting of order. We discover that the universe is
in our own hand. Our hand is in our own mind. Our
mind in our own awareness. Our awareness in our
purpose. Our purpose in our own control. Our control
in our own existence and our existence in nothing.
What began in order, will end in uniformity. To
get there, we must pass through a system of
disorder. Yet,
uniformity is our beginning.
Who are we?
When will our time lose its meaning?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="youtube-video"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/mPXnUxhrTO4?rel=0&amp;amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allow="encrypted-media" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>destiny</category><category>fate</category><category>future</category><category>time</category><guid>http://twohourslate.com/posts/contradictions-of-life/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 01:30:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Turtle Turds</title><link>http://twohourslate.com/posts/turtle_turds/</link><dc:creator>revo</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="http://twohourslate.com/images/share-preview.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;The world is not knowable. The whole world is knowable only through observation. The only way to observe is in person. In person is being there, and being is the only thing that makes a person experience something. Being there to see it, kinda like life - just here to see it, to see where it leads. Who knows, maybe we are living on a big turtle about to shit a new universe. That the whole universe exists on the inner surface of a bubble from a turtle fart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does the world add up to? What are these rocks, this dirt, trees, concrete, lakes, clouds, birds. Down to the inner core of liquefied iron up to the communication satellites beaming HBO to somebody's 45th floor apartment. Everything in between, every bit of every hundred page email thread and every pixel in every 4KHD bigscreen. From the coffee bean that made it to your palate only after it grew, was picked, shipped, washed, dried, shipped, warehoused, shipped, roasted, bagged, shipped again, measured, brewed, and then thrown away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That coffee bean had a way more interesting life after picking. Or did it? It could have been picked, digested, transported, discarded, buried, moistened, cracked, emerged, grown and revealed again. Can you imagine how few beans enjoy the second route? Very few. Most get consumed by the higher order. All for a short buzz of vibrancy that we could have found by nurturing the bean in its way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nurture nature to get a buzz.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>existential absurdity</category><category>nature</category><category>process</category><category>purpose</category><guid>http://twohourslate.com/posts/turtle_turds/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 06:13:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Creature Comforts</title><link>http://twohourslate.com/posts/creature-comforts/</link><dc:creator>revo</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from The Prophet by Kahlil Gibran&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One hundred and forty fourth printing, Sept 2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from on houses: p32-33&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or have you only comfort, and the lust for comfort, that stealthy thing that enters the house a guest, and then becomes a host, and then a master.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ay, and it becomes a tamer, and with hook and scourge makes puppets of your larger desires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though its hands are silken, its heart is of iron.
It lulls you to sleep only to stand by your bed and jeer at the dignity of the flesh.
It makes mock of your sound senses, and lays them in the thistledown like frail vessels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verily the lust for comfort murders the passion of the soul, and then walks grinning in the funeral.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>comfort</category><category>desire</category><guid>http://twohourslate.com/posts/creature-comforts/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 17:49:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Animals and Stars</title><link>http://twohourslate.com/posts/animals-and-stars/</link><dc:creator>revo</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Look up at night! If you live in the city you probably don't see much. We have polluted the night sky with our desire to be constantly in motion, to be constantly entertained and be constantly surrounded by light. I like the dark. I like it really dark and I like to be outside when it's really dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really can't tell if other animals see the milky way and wonder. Isn't that what makes us human in a way? To look up and feel small and yet be so full of wonder and amazement. I say that the Milky Way is in some ways responsible for human progress. At some point our brains were able to appreciate the heavens. Today, we overlook it and many haven't even seen it. Isn't it silly that this opportunity is not valued? To see the stars - I propose that it is one of the important factors that set us apart from other animals.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>cosmos</category><guid>http://twohourslate.com/posts/animals-and-stars/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 01:35:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>vagrant</title><link>http://twohourslate.com/posts/vagrant/</link><dc:creator>revo</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Need vagrant and virtualbox-qt. BIOS needs to allow virtualization. Then create folder and vagrant init with link to box file followed by a vagrant up and vagrant ssh. When done vagrant halt.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>linux</category><guid>http://twohourslate.com/posts/vagrant/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 23:55:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Installing Ubuntu Mate</title><link>http://twohourslate.com/posts/ubuntu-mate-install/</link><dc:creator>revo</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;First to unxz things.
Then dd the bs from if to of.
Then resize2fs the ./dev part.
Sounds crazy, I know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- code-block:

unxz ubuntu-mate-16.04-desktop-armhf-raspberry-pi.img.xz ./Ubuntu-MATE/
sudo dd bs=4M if=./Ubuntu-MATE/ubuntu-mate-16.04-desktop-armhf-raspberry-pi.img of=/dev/sdf --&gt;</description><category>linux</category><guid>http://twohourslate.com/posts/ubuntu-mate-install/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 23:51:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Something Gives</title><link>http://twohourslate.com/posts/something-gives/</link><dc:creator>revo</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Money &amp;amp; peace. They really are more aligned than one would think. Without money, how would one go about getting all of the things that the human soul has deep in the echo filled well of desire? How would there be diversification of labor? Specialization, and to a large degree progress requires the collective interests that money promotes. Money is second only to language in giving humanity the social tools necessary for cooperation. However, just like too many words doesn't get you much peace so too much money doesn't get you many friends. Now a moment of silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when money causes war? Money doesn't cause war. Suffering causes war. Money doesn't alleviate suffering, but giving it does. Words cannot be bought and money cannot buy dialogue.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>work</category><guid>http://twohourslate.com/posts/something-gives/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 02:30:21 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>